<?xml version="1.0"?>

<document>
  <properties>
    <title>NYX - "Not Yet Xulux"</title>
    <author email="martin@mvdb.net">Martin van den Bemt</author>
  </properties>

<body>

<section name="Introduction to NYX">
<p>
  The main goals of NYX is to provide an easy way
  to create frontends. The Frontend API that will
  result from the development of NYX will provide
  an easy way to migrate current application to NYX and
  reuse the components that are already created or used
  by that application.
  The API allows easy integration of widgets and gui
  layers, rule engines and dataproviders.
  We aim to provide a default set of implementations
  to get a professional frontend up and running in no time
  and this way provide an easy look into the workings
  of NYX.
  Please understand that this is a work in progress and 
  by far doesn't yet offer the functionality specified 
  above. Also much of the documentation that is provided
  is what is meant to be and not necessarily what is (yet).
  Please have a look at the <a href="features.html">features</a>
  page to see in more detail what we are going to provide.
</p>
</section>
<section name="What's up with the name??">
  <p>
  My main goal (not in life btw ;) is to get xulux up and running, 
  but I just haven't found the time yet to make time available
  to make the "perfect" solution, I started to solve some immediate 
  problems. Since the project could be usefull for the xulux project 
  in terms of learning experience (at least for me), it just isn't 
  xulux yet. To not mess up a project with higher goals, my opinion
  is that it also doesn't belong at that codebase.
  So there was the name <b>Not Yet Xulux</b>, in short <b>NYX</b>.<br/>
  NYX, pronounced with a dutch tongue in Holland, actually translates
  to the enlgish word <b>nothing</b> (which I hope this will not end up 
  as that ;)).
  According to the website <a href="http://homepage.mac.com/cparada/GML/Nyx.html" target="new">Greek Methology Link</a> Nyx is this :
  </p>
  <p>
  <b>Nyx is Night, a powerful goddess whose dark light falls from the stars, and who dictates not only to men but also to gods. Even Zeus does not wish to upset Night</b>
  </p>
  <p> 
    Very appropiate I must say ;) I refrain myself from explenation of this
    appropiate statement for now ;)
  </p>
</section>
</body>
</document>
