<?xml version="1.0"?>

<document>
  <properties>
    <title>XULUX - "ZooLLooks"</title>
    <author email="martin@mvdb.net">Martin van den Bemt</author>
  </properties>

<body>

<section name="Introduction to XULUX">
<p>
  The main goals of XULUX is to provide an easy way
  to create frontends. The Frontend API that will
  result from the development of XULUX will provide
  an easy way to migrate current applications to XULUX and
  reuse the components that are already created or used
  by that application.
  The API allows easy integration of widgets and gui
  layers, rule engines and dataproviders.
  We aim to provide a default set of implementations
  to get a professional frontend up and running in no time
  and this way provide an easy look into the workings
  of XULUX.
  Please understand that this is a work in progress and 
  by far doesn't yet offer the functionality specified 
  above. Also much of the documentation that is provided
  is what is meant to be and not necessarily what is (yet).
  Please have a look at the <a href="features.html">features</a>
  page to see in more detail what we are going to provide.
</p>
</section>
<section name="NYX and XULUX">
  <p>
    The previous version of XULUX was called NYX, which is now obsoleted. 
    You will still encounter the name NYX a lot of times in code and docs, but
    these will slowly migrate to be called XULUX or will be named differently
    in case of class names.
  </p>
</section>
<section name="Releases">
  <p>
   Currently there are no releases of XULUX. Not even an alpha release.
   Since XULUX currrently still is a moving target, I think it is best to 
   not have any releases, until the API stabelises. There are still some major 
   things on the list to get done :
   <ul>
    <li>
       Finalize the dataprovider API and add some examples / dataproviders 
       besides the current bean implementation.
    </li>
    <li>
       Refactor of widgets. All widgets should be constructed out of eg 
       PropertyHandlers, that handle all construction of widgets dynamically.
       Currently it is impossible to extend widgets without a lot of code
       duplication. Also changing the way the widget looks dynamically (eg
       background color, etc) is far from efficient.
    </li>
    <li>
       Move out the rule engine functionality from the core and start using
       interfaces and make the rule engine flexible.
    </li>
    <li>
       XULUX needs a lot of profiling to get it faster and more efficient.
       A lot of effort is currently in profiling, but currently not efficient
       enough.
    </li>
    <li>
      Add more testing. The current test coverage is about 50%, which should
      be more than 80% as far as I am concerned.
    </li>
    <li>
      Start removing the really old stuff in xulux that is holding back a big
      cleanup of code. 
    </li>
    <li>
      Write huge amounts of docs and write some nice examples. Currently it can
      be hard to start with xulux and although src/iutest gives some pointers
      on how to use xulux, it is hardly comparable with a real world example.
    </li>
    <li>
      A nice Xulux IDE to make xulux application. Preferrably build in XULUX
      , but an Eclipse plugin would be nice too..
    </li>
   </ul>
  </p>
</section>
</body>
</document>
