<?xml version="1.0"?>

<document>
  <properties>
    <title>XULUX- Gui Layers</title>
    <author email="martin@mvdb.net">Martin van den Bemt</author>
  </properties>

<body>

<section name="Gui Layers">
  <p>
    XULUX is a framework to be able to build gui layer independent application.
    Every GuiLayer is pluggable and work is under way to combine different
    gui layers in one application. 
  </p>
</section>
<section name="Implementations">
  <p>
    These are the gui layers that would be interesting to have it implemented.
  </p>
  <subsection name="Swing">
    <p>
      The swing implementation is in alpha state atm. Components are still missing
      or not enough properties are supported yet to tweak everything that a 
      component needs. The components are created based on the need that I have
      to create it.
      See the <a href="swing/index.html">Swing Pages</a> for more information about
      the current implementation. See the <a href="widgets/index.html">Widget docs</a>
      if you want to know which widgets are currently available.
    </p>
  </subsection>
  <subsection name="SWT">
    <p>
      Started on SWT and had the nice plan to implement Widgets immidiately after
      implementing the Swing Widget. However because of time constrains, I could
      not handle that. If I have more time and the core (the frontend API) 
      of nyx has been finished, I will start programming SWT support.
      See the <a href="swt/index.html">SWT Pages</a> for more information about
      the current implementation. See the <a href="widgets/index.html">Widget docs</a>
    </p>
  </subsection>
  <subsection name="AWT">
    <p>
      Nice to have for pda's, phones, etc. 
    </p>
  </subsection>
  <subsection name="Servlets/HTML">
    <p>
      Usefull to be able to present your application also on the net, without
      needing a rewrite. Since there are some limitations to showing a gui
      in html / js, there probably needs to be some kind of templating system.
      Needs furthur investigation. 
    </p>
  </subsection>
  <subsection name="Others">
    <p>
      Got any pointers to other java gui implementations? Let them know!
    </p>
  </subsection>
</section>
<section name="Goals">
  <p>
    I am currently in the process of generalizing everything and splitting
    up widgets, so peaces of functionality can be mapped and overriden.
    Generalising probably has some limitations, but those will be investigated
    when needed.
  </p>
</section>
<section name="Current limitations">
  <p>
    The current limitation of the gui layer API is that the different gui layers
    cannot be combined yet (although the code might pretend differently)
    This will be implemented when a second layer is finished or in progress.
  </p>
</section>
</body>

</document>
