<?xml version="1.0"?>

<document>
  <properties>
    <title>NYX - The Combo Widget</title>
    <author email="martin@mvdb.net">Martin van den Bemt</author>
  </properties>

<body>

<section name="The Combo Widget">
  <subsection name="General">
    <p>
      Explain what the combo does
    </p>
  </subsection>
  <subsection name="Content and Selected Value">
    <p>
      When you set a value in the combo, nyx will set
      the selected value in the list accordingly.
      If the value is not found, it will set the selected
      value to the first entry in the list.
    </p>
    <p>
      If you replace the content and in between the value
      is never set, it will try to use the current value
      to select the correct item. If the item is not in the
      list, it will reset the current value to be the first
      item.
    </p>
  </subsection>
  <subsection name="Properties">
    <p>
      This is a list of all supported combo specific properties.
      See the <a href="index.html">widget page</a> for information
      about properties used for all widgets.
    </p>
    <table>
      <tr><th>property</th><th>supported</th><th>description</th></tr>
      <tr>
        <td>notselectedvalue</td>
        <td>swing, swt</td>
        <td>
           Specify a not selected value, so the combo can show
           that value when no item has been selected.
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>content</td>
        <td>swing</td>
        <td>
            The dictionary field or a comma seperated
            list of values.
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>content.type</td>
        <td>swing</td>
        <td>
          This specifies the type of content.
          Valid values are string (comma seperated list of 
          values) or field, which should map to an entry
          in the dictionary. Currently only a static method
          is supported if the bean is null.
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>others</td>
        <td>swing, swt</td>
        <td>
          The default widget properties.
        </td>
      </tr>
    </table>
  </subsection>
  <subsection name="Swing notes">
    <h3>Overriden JComboBox NyxCombo</h3>
    <p>
      We had to override the swing combobox since it was
      firing of too many events in case of setting new content.
      Since it would loose the selectedValue during the setting
      of the new content,I had to do some overriding of the setModel 
      to prevent that from happening.
    </p>
    <h3>Current problems</h3>
    <p>
      The combo, using swing, will not select a
      value (visually) if the selected value is below the 
      initial viewable size (as far as I could see). 
      It doesn't have any consequences for the workings of the
      combo however. I think the problem is related to messages
      being sent or not being sent. (the model doesn't do 
      anything with listeners for example)
    </p>
  </subsection>
</section>

</body>

</document>
