<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!-- $Id: index.xml,v 1.1.2.1 2003-05-04 15:27:41 mvdb Exp $ -->
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>NYX - Swing Specifics</title>
    <author email="martin@mvdb.net">Martin van den Bemt</author>
  </properties>

<body>

<section name="Focusmanagement">
  <subsection name="General">
    <p>
      You can set the tab order of widgets via the order element
      in the xml of the part. Nyx adds a JPanel in front of the
      defined xml, where all controls will reside. The container
      for the panel however is not yet provided by nyx (at 
      least in the tocure version). 
      Since nyx has no control over the container of the rootpanel
      and jdk 1.3 has a horrible way of handling the initial focussed 
      field
    </p>
  </subsection>
  <subsection name="Behaviour">
    <p>
      The nyx rootpanel is used as a reference. After activating
      all the widgets, the nyx focusmanager is called to set the 
      correct focussed field. This will startup a separate thread
      which will check when the rootpanel has a parent. If the parent
      is there, it will add an even to the current swingui to select
      the next component. The rest of the focusmanagement is triggered
      by using tab and shift-tab.
      If no order is specified in the xml, swing will set the order.
      If you just specify the order of eg 2 fields, the next
      component after those 2 fields will be the next component
      on the window, with the exception of those 2 fields.
      So if you have 3 fields, the specified taborder is 
      field2, field1 (the fields are ordered on the screen as
      field1, field2, field3) and you are in field2, hit tab, 
      the focus goes to field1, if you hit tab again, the focus 
      goed to field3, and not field2 again. 
    </p>
  </subsection>
  <subsection name="Properties">
    <p>
      type - default or custom.<br/>
      The custom type checks if a field has a value and progresses
      to the next field (if it is in the order element!) untill
      the field is empty. If from the fields all fields are filled
      with a value, it will fallback to the default behaviour.
    </p>
  </subsection>
  
  <subsection
</section>

</body>

</document>
